<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>retinar</title>
    <link>https://retinar.com.ar/</link>
    <description>Recent content on retinar</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 10:00:00 -0300</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://retinar.com.ar/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>We Presented Retinar to the Minister of Health of the Province of Buenos Aires</title>
      <link>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2025-04-kreplak/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 10:00:00 -0300</pubDate>
      <guid>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2025-04-kreplak/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Monday, March 31st, we had the honor of presenting &lt;strong&gt;Retinar&lt;/strong&gt; to the Minister of Health of the Province of Buenos Aires, &lt;strong&gt;Nicol谩s Kreplak&lt;/strong&gt;, and part of his cabinet during their visit to Tandil as part of the preparations for the &lt;strong&gt;Provincial Health Congress (COSAPRO)&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retinar Selected by the FITBA 2024 Program</title>
      <link>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2024-12-fitba/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2024 18:51:36 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2024-12-fitba/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Retinar is one of the projects selected in the third call of the Buenos Aires Technological Innovation Fund (FITBA), run by the Ministry of Production, Science, and Technological Innovation of the Province of Buenos Aires.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>We Won the Transformative AI Award!</title>
      <link>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2024-12-ia-transformadora/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Dec 2024 18:51:36 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2024-12-ia-transformadora/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We won the Transformative AI Award from the National Secretariat of Innovation, Science, and Technology!!   コ&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Guest Speakers at IADI 2024</title>
      <link>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2024-11-uca/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 18:51:36 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2024-11-uca/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We were invited as guest speakers at the 1st National Conference on Artificial Intelligence in Medical Imaging (IADI 2024), organized by the Data and Artificial Intelligence Lab of the School of Engineering and Agricultural Sciences at the Pontifical Catholic University of Argentina.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meeting for the Strengthening of the Digital Health Agenda</title>
      <link>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2024-06-ensenada/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 18:51:36 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2024-06-ensenada/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Wednesday, we spoke in Ensenada at the Meeting for the Strengthening of the Digital Health Agenda organized by the Ministry of Health of the Province of Buenos Aires. Together with Soledad Guill茅n, head of the Ophthalmology Network of the Province of Buenos Aires, we presented some statistics on diabetes and diabetic retinopathy in the region, and from Retinar we explained how our teleophthalmology system can help improve the detection and diagnosis of this disease.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Preselected in the BNA 2024 Innovative Solutions Contest</title>
      <link>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2024-08-empretec/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 18:51:36 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2024-08-empretec/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Were excited to announce that, along with 89 other projects, we were selected from over 2,900 proposals to move on to the next phase of the BNA Innovative Solutions Contest, organized by Banco de la Naci贸n Argentina and the EMPRETEC Foundation. This contest aims to promote innovative projects that contribute to the countrys economic and social development, and were honored to have been chosen among so many outstanding proposals.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retinar Wins Transformar Salud 2023</title>
      <link>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2023-07-transformar-salud/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2023 18:51:36 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2023-07-transformar-salud/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to announce that Retinar has been named the winner of the 2023 Transformar Salud edition, organized by Fundaci贸n Garrahan and Laboratorios Roche Argentina. As part of this achievement, we have received funding totaling AR$ 1,200,000 to operationalize a Minimum Viable Product (MVP), along with mentorship, tutoring, and training sessions to bring the project to life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Visit from the Minister of Health of the Nation</title>
      <link>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2023-04-vizzotti/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 18:51:36 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2023-04-vizzotti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We conducted a demonstration of our platform and discussed potential avenues to scale our project and utilize it at a national level with Carla Vizzotti, Minister of Health of the Nation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retinar Receives the 2021 Annual Award from the National Academy of Medicine</title>
      <link>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2022-12-academia-medicina/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 18:51:36 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2022-12-academia-medicina/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday afternoon, we had the honor of receiving the 2021 Award from the National Academy of Medicine of Buenos Aires for our work on @retinarARG alongside @Tomass_Castilla, Alejandro Koch, Marcela Mart铆nez, and Mercedes Legu铆a from @ElCruceHospital and Ignacio Larrabide. The work summarizes the results we achieved with @Tomass_Castilla in improving the algorithm for the detection of referable diabetic retinopathy that we developed in his undergraduate thesis, and which we recently published at #SIPAIM2022, the congress of @SIPAIM_Society.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Award for Best Oral Presentation at CNO 2022</title>
      <link>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2022-06-premio-cno/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 18:51:36 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2022-06-premio-cno/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to announce that Retinar has been honored with the award for the best scientific work presented at the 2022 National Congress of Ophthalmology (CNO).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retinar Presented at the JIS of the Italian Hospital</title>
      <link>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2021-11-jis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Nov 2021 10:07:21 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2021-11-jis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We had the privilege of presenting Retinar at the Informatics and Health Conference of the Italian Hospital. During the event, we shared insights into the first version of our diabetic retinopathy detection algorithm.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retinar Receives Funding from PAC Emprendedores para la Innovaci贸n</title>
      <link>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2021-10-pac/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 18:51:36 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2021-10-pac/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to announce that Retinar has secured funding from the Ministry of Productive Development of Argentina as part of the PAC Emprendedores para la Innovaci贸n initiative. This program aims to support the creation of technology-based SMEs to address real-world challenges. In our case, we have been awarded a non-refundable contribution of AR$ 207,000, which will be utilized to cover the costs associated with developing a navigable prototype and an initial Minimum Viable Product (MVP) of the platform.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retinar Secures Funding from Agencia I&#43;D&#43;i (Argentina)</title>
      <link>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2021-06-pict/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jun 2021 18:51:36 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2021-06-pict/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are delighted to announce that Retinar has been awarded funding through the 2021 call for PICT startups from the Agencia Nacional para la Promoci贸n de la Investigaci贸n, el Desarrollo Cient铆fico y la Innovaci贸n (Agencia I+D+i). This funding will support our ongoing research efforts in Retinar under the supervision of Dr. Jos茅 Ignacio Orlando.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retinar Recognized by NVIDIA Corporation</title>
      <link>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2021-06-nvidia-hardware-copy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jun 2021 10:07:21 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2021-06-nvidia-hardware-copy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Retinar is thrilled to announce that we have been selected as a member of the prestigious &lt;a href=&#34;https://resources.nvidia.com/en-us-gps-ai-capacity-building/applied-research-pro&#34;&gt;NVIDIA Applied Research Accelerator Program&lt;/a&gt;. Our collaborative project, titled &amp;ldquo;Retinar: Assisting Remote Diabetic Retinopathy Screening with AI Tools,&amp;rdquo; a joint initiative between UNICEN and Hospital El Cruce, has been honored with 500 hours of V100 GPU instances via SaturnCloud. Furthermore, this donation is extendable based on the project&amp;rsquo;s requirements.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retinar Secures PICT 2019 Funding from Agencia I&#43;D&#43;i</title>
      <link>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2021-02-pict/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 18:51:36 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2021-02-pict/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Retinar is thrilled to announce that our project, titled &amp;ldquo;Characterization of Optic Nerve Head Morphology from Color Fundus Pictures Using Deep Learning&amp;rdquo; (CANOA: Caracterizaci贸n Morfol贸gica de la Cabeza del Nervio ptico en Fotograf铆as de Fondo de Ojo Mediante Aprendizaje Profundo), has been awarded a PICT 2019 grant by Agencia I+D+i, the national agency for funding research. This two-year initiative will be generously funded with AR$ 475,000.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retinar Featured on Ciencia por Cientificxs</title>
      <link>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2021-05-cxc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 10:07:21 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2021-05-cxc/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On October 5th of this year, I had the privilege of participating in the first episode of the new season of Ciencia por Cientificxs, the science outreach program on AbraTV, the UNICEN TV channel. Alongside Mercedes Legu铆a from Hospital El Cruce, we showcased Retinar, our AI-assisted ophthalmological telemedicine project for the remote diagnosis of diabetic retinopathy. You can view the video right below this article:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retinar Showcased on WOW Innovation</title>
      <link>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2021-02-wow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 10:07:21 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2021-02-wow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On February 5th of this year, Retinar had the honor of being featured on the WOW Innovation segment aired on Channel 8 of Mar del Plata. We proudly presented our groundbreaking AI-assisted telemedicine project designed for the remote diagnosis of diabetic retinopathy. The program serves as a platform to spotlight innovative projects from entrepreneurs across the nation spanning various domains.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retinar is the most voted initiative at Prendete 2020</title>
      <link>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2020-12-prendete/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 12:52:36 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2020-12-prendete/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to announce that Retinar has won the popular vote at Prendete 2020, the startup contest organized in Tandil to increase the visibility of innovative initiatives. By winning this award, we have been granted USD 10,000 in AWS credits, which we will use to implement our MVP.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retinar receives a UNICEN&#39;s JOVIN Grant for R&amp;D</title>
      <link>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2020-09-prendete/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 10:07:21 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2020-09-prendete/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Retinar is proud to announce that our project, titled &amp;ldquo;Towards an Intelligent Platform for Remote Diabetic Retinopathy Screening: Quality Control in Fundus Photography Using Autoencoders,&amp;rdquo; has been awarded a JOVIN grant of AR$ 100,000 (approximately U$D 1000) by UNICEN. This grant is part of the Program for Strengthening Science and Technology in National Universities, initiated by the Secretariat of Science, Art, and Technology at UNICEN.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retinar receives a UNICEN&#39;s JOVIN Grant for R&amp;D</title>
      <link>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2020-11-jovin/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Nov 2020 10:07:21 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2020-11-jovin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Retinar is proud to announce that our project, titled &amp;ldquo;Towards an Intelligent Platform for Remote Diabetic Retinopathy Screening: Quality Control in Fundus Photography Using Autoencoders,&amp;rdquo; has been awarded a JOVIN grant of AR$ 100,000 (approximately U$D 1000) by UNICEN. This grant is part of the Program for Strengthening Science and Technology in National Universities, initiated by the Secretariat of Science, Art, and Technology at UNICEN.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Retinar joins Prendete 2020</title>
      <link>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2020-08-prendete/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 12:52:36 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2020-08-prendete/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are thrilled to announce our participation in the 2020 edition of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.prendete.com.ar/&#34;&gt;Prendete&lt;/a&gt;, an innovative business ideas contest. Prendete is a national contest organized in Tandil since 2015, aimed at aiding the development of innovative business initiatives and being a launchpad for viable, scalable projects that can generate more employment opportunities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Our new website is live!</title>
      <link>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2020-08-website/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2020 12:52:36 +0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://retinar.com.ar/blog/2020-08-website/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;We are delighted to announce the launch of our new website. This platform is designed to keep you informed about all our latest developments and news in real time. We created this site to provide clear and accessible information about Retinar and our initiatives, especially as we gear up to participate in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.prendete.com.ar/&#34;&gt;Prendete, the innovative business ideas contest in Tandil&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
